Guide to the Annie Burr Lewis Papers
The Lewis Walpole Library
- Family Papers, 1849–1960; Series III; 6.76; 8 boxes
  - Annie Burr Jennings Papers
    - Estate records
      - Preliminary account, Connecticut probate court, 1940 (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Financial Records, 1926–1959; Series IV; 8.13; 21 boxes
  Series IV is organized into two subseries: Bank Accounts, and Investment Accounts.
  The series holds both Annie Lewis's checking account records and those of her investments managed by her brother Hugh D. Auchincloss and members of his firm Auchincloss, Parker & Redpath. The bulk of the series is comprised of check registers from the two New York banks and one Hartford bank she patronized from the 1920s until her death. Also here are the registers from the Lewises' years living in Washington, D.C. When available, cancelled checks were retained to fill some gaps where check registers could not be found when the papers were processed in 2017-2018.
  - Bank Accounts
    Annie Lewis's check registers document her life and lifestyle; checks were recorded by Lewis or her assistant Gertrude Manly, and show expenses for taxes, dogs, automobiles, and staff; payment of dues and house tabs in private clubs in New York, Connecticut, and Rhode Island; and contributions to charities in those states. Many of the checks were written for purchases in shops such as Hartford's G. Fox, and New York's Henri Bendel, Bonwit Teller, Hammacher Schlemmer, and Steuben Glass, as well as for goods and services received from the Hartford decorators Maritje Jacobus and Henry Saling, and furniture maker Nathan Margolis, and the decorator Elizabeth Draper in New York. Another regular expense was photography, and many checks were written to Pavelle Laboratories for developing film and printing the pictures taken by Annie Lewis that appear throughout the Lewises' photograph collection (LWL MSS 22).
    - Farmers' Loan and Trust Company (New York, N.Y.)
      - Check registers, 1926 January–1929 July (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
    - National City Bank of New York
      - Check registers, 1929 July–1935 December (Box 30, Folder 1-7)
        Lacking registers covering February to August 1931, and January 1932 to March 1933.
      - Check registers and cancelled checks, 1936 January–1937 October (Box 31, Folder 1-7)
        Lacking registers covering January to May 1936, and October 1936 to May 1937. Folder 1 holds a register for a pocket checkbook that Annie Lewis used from July 1936 through September 1946.
      - Check registers and cancelled checks, 1937 October–1938 December (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
        Lacking register covering October to December 1937.
      - Check registers, 1938 December–1940 July (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
      - Check registers, 1940 July–1942 October (Box 34, Folder 1-5)
        Lacking register covering July to November 1941.
      - Check registers, 1942 October–1944 July (Box 35, Folder 1-4)
      - Check registers, 1944 July–1946 August (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
      - Monogrammed leather check register cover, circa 1946 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Check registers, 1946 August–1948 May (Box 37, Folder 2-6)
      - Check registers, 1948 May–1949 December (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
      - Check registers and cancelled checks, 1950 January–1950 December (Box 39, Folder 1-5)
      - Check registers, 1955 March–1956 July (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
        Lacking registers covering January 1951 to March 1955.
      - Check registers and cancelled checks, 1956 July–1959 December (Box 41, Folder 1-6)
        Lacking register covering mid-June 1957 to October 1957, and January-March 1959.
      - Checkbooks for Paris branch, 1933 August–1939 April (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Checkbooks and cancelled checks for London branch, 1935 August–1941 March (Box 42, Folder 2-4)
    - Hartford National Bank and Trust Company, 1945–1957 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Records of trust accounts set up for Hugh and Agnes Ross, Lily Duncan, Helen M. Scarth, and the Sarah Porter Centenary Fund.
    - Hartford-Connecticut Trust Company
      - Check registers, 1928 June–1934 April (Box 43, Folder 1-4)
      - Check registers, 1934 April–1946 January (Box 44, Folder 1-6)
      - Check registers and cancelled checks, 1946 January–1949 November (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
    - Riggs National Bank (Washington, D.C.)
      - Check registers, 1941 September–1946 May (Box 46, Folder 1-4)
  - Investment Accounts
    - Auchincloss, Parker & Redpath, 1940–1952 (Box 47, Folder 1-10)
    - Auchincloss, Parker & Redpath, 1953–1956 (Box 48, Folder 1-4)
    - Auchincloss, Parker & Redpath, 1957–1959 (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
    - Interest on Bonds, 1940s–1950s (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Small loose-leaf notebook with Julia McCarthy's notes on interest earned.
- American Red Cross Records, 1941–1946; Series V; 0.63; 2 boxes
  Series V is organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Connecticut Camp and Hospital Committee, and Other Papers.
  The Lewises moved to Washington, DC, in the fall of 1941 when Wilmarth Lewis accepted an appointment as chief of the Information Division in the Office of Strategic Services. Upon arrival, Annie Lewis offered her services to the National Headquarters of the American Red Cross. She held two positions with the organization: assistant director of Volunteer Special Services (1941-1944) and, once she returned to Farmington in 1943, as a Volunteer Field Representative for Camp and Hospital Service, (1944-1946).
  The series primarily contains records from Annie Lewis's service in Connecticut (1944-1946), and includes copies of memos and reports sent from and to the North Atlantic Office in New York. Also here are reports she wrote after her visits to cities and towns around the state, as well as correspondence about programs and events being organized for veterans.
  The contents of the files were not arranged; the papers were rehoused in 2018 and titles from the original files were repurposed for this finding aid.
  - Correspondence
    - Camp and Hospital Council Service, 1944–1946 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
      Correspondence with the North Atlantic Office in New York.
    - General Field Representatives itineraries, 1945–1946 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Area to Council Chairmen, 1944–1945 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Area directives, 1944–1946 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Council Chairman, 1944–1945 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut Camp and Hospital Committee
    - Contact lists, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
      Includes a map of Connecticut.
    - Correspondence, 1944–1946 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Entertainment Committee, 1944–1946 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Meeting minutes, 1944–1946 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Chapter monthly reports, 1943–1946 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      As the state of Connecticut's representative, Annie Lewis received copies of all monthly reports issued by chapters around the state.
    - Itineraries, 1944–1946 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Council Field Representative Chapter Visit reports, 1944–1946 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Other Papers
    - Services to the Armed Forces memos, 1943–1945 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Army and Navy Auxiliaries, 1944–1945 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Red Cross badges, button, and other uniform items, circa 1943 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1943, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Includes Annie Lewis in a group photograph taken at the Red Cross convention in Los Angeles, 1943, and volunteers posing with actor Walter Pidgeon. Her official portrait photographs are filed in the Lewises' photograph collection (LWL MSS 22), Box 5, Folder 10.
    - Public relations, 1942–1945 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Includes an article on Annie Lewis published in the Washington Star, October 15, 1942.
    - The Councilor, 1944–1945 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Issues of the Camp and Hospitals Councils newsletter for February, August, September, and December 1944, with editorial policy memo.
    - Certificate of Appreciation, 1946 January 21 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Suggestions for Conducting Meetings, by Sarah Corbin Robert, 1941 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      Booklet published for the use of Volunteer Special Services.